oztips.com 2015-11-12

# PRIVACY POLICY

## WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVERS

**Yahoo!7 takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy.**

**How Yahoo!7 Uses Your Personal Information**

Yahoo!7 complies with the Australian Privacy Principles (“APPs”). This Privacy Policy covers how Yahoo!7 treats personal information that Yahoo!7 collects and receives, including information related to your past use of Yahoo!7 products and services. Personal information is information or opinion about an individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable (whether the information or opinion is true or not, and whether the information or opinion is recorded in a material form) and includes (but is not limited to) the following kinds of information: your name, address, email address, phone number and so on.

**This Privacy Policy only applies to Yahoo!7**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Yahoo!7 does not own or control, or to people that Yahoo!7 does not employ or manage. In addition, some companies that Yahoo!7 is affiliated with have their own privacy policies which may be viewed on our [acquired companies page](https://policies.yahoo.com/us/en/yahoo/privacy/topics/acquiredcompanies/index.html).

By using Yahoo!7’s products and services, you consent to Yahoo!7 using your personal information as set out in this Privacy Policy.

## INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE

**General**

Yahoo!7 collects personal information when you register with Yahoo!7, when you use Yahoo or Yahoo!7’s [products or services](http://info.yahoo.com/privacy/au/yahoo/products.html), when you visit Yahoo!7 pages or the pages of certain Yahoo!7 partners, and when you enter [promotions or competitions](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/products/promotions/index.htm). Yahoo!7 may combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from business partners or other companies.

When you register we ask for information such as your name, email address, birth date, gender, post code, occupation, industry, and personal interests. When you register with Yahoo!7 and sign in to our services, you are not anonymous to us.

Yahoo!7 collects information about your transactions with us and with some of our business partners, including information about your use of financial products and services that we offer.

Yahoo!7 automatically receives and records information from your computer and browser, including your [IP address](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/topics/ipaddresses/index.html), Yahoo [cookie](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/topics/cookies/index.html) information, software and hardware attributes, and the page you request.

Yahoo!7 uses information for the following general purposes: to customise the advertising and content you see, fulfill your requests for products and services, improve our services, contact you, conduct research, and provide anonymous reporting for internal and external clients

You may choose to deal with Yahoo!7 anonymously or under a pseudonym where lawful and practicable.

## INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE

Yahoo!7 does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or non-affiliated companies except to provide products or services you have requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances:

  * We provide the information, in compliance with the Australian Privacy Principles, to trusted partners who work on behalf of or with Yahoo!7 under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your personal information to help Yahoo!7 communicate with you about offers from Yahoo!7 and our marketing partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information, except to the extent required by law.
  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.
  * We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Yahoo!7’s terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.
  * We transfer information about you if Yahoo!7 is acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, Yahoo!7 will notify you before information about you is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

Yahoo!7 displays targeted advertisements based on personal information. Advertisers (including ad serving companies) may assume that people who interact with, view, or click targeted ads meet the targeting criteria—for example, women ages 18-24 from a particular geographic area.

  * Yahoo!7 does not provide any personal information to the advertiser when you interact with or view a targeted ad. However, by interacting with or viewing an ad you are consenting to the possibility that the advertiser will make the assumption that you meet the targeting criteria used to display the ad.
  * Yahoo!7 advertisers include financial service providers (such as banks, insurance agents, stock brokers and mortgage lenders) and non-financial companies (such as stores, airlines, and software companies).

Yahoo!7 works with vendors, partners, advertisers, and other service providers in different industries and categories of business. For more information regarding providers of products or services that you have requested please read our detailed [reference links](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/products/index.html).

On some occasions your personal information may need to be transferred to overseas countries including the United States, Ireland, Singapore, Korea, United Kingdom, Austria, and Taiwan in order to perform one or more of Yahoo!7’s functions or activities and you consent to such transfer and acknowledge that Section 8.1 of the Australian Privacy Principles will not apply to such transfer.

## COOKIES

Yahoo!7 may set and access Yahoo!7 [cookies](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/topics/cookies/index.html) on your computer.

Yahoo!7 lets [other companies](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/topics/thirdparties/index.html) that show advertisements on some of our pages set and access their cookies on your computer. Other companies' use of their cookies is subject to their own privacy policies, not this one. Advertisers or other companies do not have access to Yahoo!7’s cookies.

Yahoo!7 uses [web beacons](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/topics/webbeacons/index.html) to access Yahoo!7 cookies inside and outside our network of websites and in connection with Yahoo!7 products and services.

## YOUR ABILITY TO ACCESS, EDIT AND DELETE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AND PREFERENCES

You can access and edit/correct your [Yahoo!7 Account Information](http://edit.yahoo.com/config/eval_profile), including your [marketing preferences](http://subscribe.yahoo.com/showaccount), at any time.

New categories of marketing communications might be added to the Marketing Preferences page from time to time. Users who visit this page can opt out of receiving future marketing communications from these new categories or they can unsubscribe by following instructions contained in the messages they receive.

We reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to the Yahoo!7 service, such as service announcements, administrative messages and the Yahoo!7 Newsletter, that are considered part of your Yahoo!7 account, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.

You may also request access to and correction of the personal information Yahoo!7 holds about you by writing to the Privacy Officer. Additionally, you may delete your Yahoo!7 account by visiting our [Account Deletion](https://edit.yahoo.com/config/delete_user) page. Please [click here](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/topics/datastorage/index.html) to read about information that might possibly remain in our archived records after your account has been deleted.

## CONFIDENTIALITY AND SECURITY

We limit access to personal information about you to our employees or those of our related bodies corporate who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs.

We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations to protect personal information about you.

To learn more about security, including the security steps Yahoo!7 has taken and security steps you can take, please read [Security at Yahoo!7](https://policies.yahoo.com/au/en/yahoo/privacy/topics/security/index.html).

## CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Yahoo!7 may update this policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your Yahoo!7 account or by placing a prominent notice on our site.

## QUESTIONS, COMPLAINTS AND SUGGESTIONS

If you have questions or suggestions, please complete a [feedback form](https://io.help.yahoo.com/contact/index?page=contact&locale=en_AU&y=PROD_ACCT). Complaints about a breach of the APPs must be addressed in writing to:

Privacy Officer c/- Legal Department  
Yahoo!7 Pty Limited  
PO Box R1469  
ROYAL EXCHANGE  
NSW 1225 Australia

We will notify you within 14 working days of the Privacy Officer receiving your complaint and will try to resolve the complaint within 30 working days. When this is not possible we will contact you to provide an estimate of the time it will take to resolve the complaint.

_Last updated: March 12, 2014_
